<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US" xml:base="http://www.cafeconleche.org/today.atom">
  <logo>/images/cup.gif</logo>
  <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
  <updated>2007-02-21T11:00:02-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/</id>
  <title>Cafe con Leche XML News and Resources</title>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/today.atom"/>
  <subtitle>Cafe con Leche is the preeminent independent source of XML information on the net. Cafe con Leche is neither beholden to specific companies nor to advertisers. At Cafe con Leche you'll find many resources to help you develop your XML skills here including daily news summaries, examples, book reviews, mailing lists and more.</subtitle>
  <rights>Copyright 2007 Elliotte Rusty Harold</rights>
  <author>
    <name>Elliotte Rusty Harold</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Quote of the Day</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <blockquote>
          <div>
Opera, Safari, Konquerer and Mozilla all support SVG. Microsoft uses VML, which is poorly documented, poorly implemented, has strong dependencies on Microsoft libraries and has been "frozen" since the mid-1990s. When Adobe's SVG plugin support expires in 2008, how many people who are depending upon SVG for their applications (such as the city of Toronto, not a small customer by any means) will just decide to refactor their applications to work on Mozilla and jettison their reliance on IE. When XForms support becomes integrated into Mozilla as part of the core suite (mid-summer 2007) how many customers of Infopath will start to see this as a commercially viable alternative? Or when Opera and Safari follow suit? How many web developers will just say "to hell with it" because IE's JavaScript support (excuse me, JScript support) doesn't even bother to support getters or setters, and the costs of maintaining two code bases gets to be too onerous. No, the lagging users are still firmly in the MIcrosoft camp, but the leading edge has been dropping IE in favor of alternatives at a far higher rate than the ones that are going the other way.

</div>
        </blockquote>
        <p>--Kurt Cagle
on the xml-dev mailing list, 
Saturday, 20 Jan 2007 16:28:26 </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Kurt Cagle on the xml-dev mailing list, Saturday, 20 Jan 2007 16:28:26</name>
    </author>
    <link href="/#quote"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/quotes2007.html#quote2007February19</id>
    <updated>2007-02-19T09:15:25Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C HTML Working Group has posted a new working draft of XML Events 2.
          "The XML Events module defined in this specification provides XML languages with the ability to uniformly integrate event listeners and associated event handlers with Document Object Model (DOM) Level 2 event interfaces [DOM2EVENTS].
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_19_2007_33160" class="2007-02-19T09:13:40Z">

<p>
The W3C HTML Working Group has posted a new working draft of <a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/WD-xml-events-20070216">XML
Events 2</a>. "The XML Events module defined in this specification provides XML languages with the ability to uniformly integrate event listeners and associated event handlers with Document Object Model (DOM) Level 2 event interfaces [DOM2EVENTS]. The result is to provide an interoperable way of associating behaviors with document-level markup." According to Mark Birbeck,
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>
Although it was produced by the HTML Working Group (editors of this
version being Shane McCarron and myself), it has features that are
specifically geared towards future versions of XForms.
</p>

<p>
Some of the interesting new features are the ability to register and
remove handlers at run-time, and the ev:script element, which allows
action handlers to be created using script. This means that script can
be interspersed with other action handlers.
</p>

</blockquote>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_19_2007_33160"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_19_2007_33160</id>
    <updated>2007-02-19T09:13:40Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ActiveState has posted released Komodo 4.0.2, a $295 payware IDE for Perl, Ruby, PHP, Python, Tcl, and XSLT.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_17_2007_61616" class="2007-02-17T17:07:56Z">
<p>
ActiveState has posted released  <a shape="rect" href="http://www.activestate.com/Products/Komodo/">Komodo 4.0.2</a>, a $295 payware 
<acronym title="integrated development environment">IDE</acronym> for Perl, Ruby, PHP, Python, Tcl, and <em>XSLT</em>. Komodo runs on Mac OS X 10.3 and later, Linux, and Windows.  They've also release <a shape="rect" href="http://www.activestate.com/Products/komodo_edit/">Komodo Edit</a> which looks like a free-as-in-lite-beer
version of Komodo. 
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_17_2007_61616"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_17_2007_61616</id>
    <updated>2007-02-17T17:07:56Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C Voice Browser, Web APIs and Web Application Formats (WAF) Working Groups have posted a new version of Enabling Read Access for Web Resources (formerly Authorizing Read Access to XML Content Using the &lt;?access-control?&gt; Processing Instruction 1.0).
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_16_2007_37442" class="2007-02-16T10:24:02Z">
<p>
The W3C Voice Browser, Web APIs and Web Application Formats (WAF) Working Groups have posted a new version of  <a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/WD-access-control-20070215/">Enabling Read Access for Web Resources</a> (formerly Authorizing Read Access to XML Content Using the &lt;?access-control?&gt; Processing Instruction 1.0). According to the draft,
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>
A plethora of applications and data are exposed as XML over HTTP. User agents such as Voice and Web browsers fetch and execute applications but restrict the XML content accessible to those applications merely to the URLs located in the same domain as the application. To take advantage of the rich XML content available on the Web, application developers must resort to proxying the content through the domain hosting their application thereby increasing overhead and limiting scalability.
</p>

<p>
This note describes a mechanism being used in the industry that allows a content provider to use a processing instruction embedded within the XML prolog to specify the access policy of that content. In this model a user agent can safely extend the sandbox in which it has restricted the application to include access to the XML content if and only if the specified policy grants permission.
</p>

<p>
The processing instruction is designed explicitly to enable extending the sandbox and is not designed as a restriction mechanism. The expectation is that the user agent's default policy is more strict. Therefore, it is always safe to fall-back to default policy in the event of an error.
</p>

<p>
ISSUE: The Task Force would like to enable this mechanism as an HTTP header (e.g. Content-Access-Control). We expect to apply this change to a later draft.
</p>

</blockquote>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_16_2007_37442"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_16_2007_37442</id>
    <updated>2007-02-16T10:24:02Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C Web Services Activity.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_15_2007_33549" class="2007-02-15T09:19:09Z">
<p>
The W3C Web Services Activity.
has posted the candidate recommendation of 
<a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/CR-sawsdl-20070126/">Semantic Annotations for WSDL</a>. According to the draft,
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>
Semantic Annotations for WSDL and XML Schema (SAWSDL) defines how to add semantic annotations to various parts of a WSDL document such as input and output message structures, interfaces and operations. The extension attributes defined in this specification fit within the WSDL 2.0 extensibility framework. For example, it defines a way to annotate WSDL interfaces and operations with categorization information that can be used to publish a Web service in a registry. The annotations on schema types can be used during Web service discovery and composition. In addition, SAWSDL defines an annotation mechanism for specifying the structural mapping of XML Schema types to and from an ontology such mappings could be used during invocation, particularly when mediation is required. To accomplish semantic annotation, SAWSDL defines extension attributes that can be applied both to WSDL elements and to XML Schema elements.
</p>

<p>
Semantic annotations are references from an element within a WSDL or XML Schema document to a concept in an ontology or to a mapping. This specification defines annotation mechanisms for relating the constituent structures of WSDL input and output messages to concepts defined in an outside ontology. Similarly, it defines how to annotate WSDL operations and interfaces. Further, it defines an annotation mechanism for specifying the structural mapping of XML Schema types to and from an ontology by means of a reference to a mapping definition. The annotation mechanism is independent of the ontology expression language and this specification requires no particular ontology language. It is also independent of mapping languages and does not restrict the possible choices of such languages.
</p>


</blockquote>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_15_2007_33549"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_15_2007_33549</id>
    <updated>2007-02-15T09:19:09Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C CSS Working Group has posted a new working draft of CSS3 module: Generated Content for Paged Media that "describes how CSS style sheets can express named strings, leaders, cross-references, footnotes, endnotes, running headers and footers, named flows, new counter styles, page and column floats, hyphenation, bookmarks, change bars, continuation markers, named page lists, and generated lists."</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_14_2007_36991" class="2007-02-14T10:17:31Z">
<p>
The W3C CSS Working Group has posted a new working draft of <a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/WD-css3-gcpm-20070205/">CSS3 module: Generated Content for Paged Media</a> that 
"describes how CSS style sheets can express named strings, leaders, cross-references, footnotes, endnotes, running headers and footers, named flows, new counter styles, page and column floats, hyphenation, bookmarks, change bars, continuation markers, named page lists, and generated lists."
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_14_2007_36991"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_14_2007_36991</id>
    <updated>2007-02-14T10:17:31Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C CSS Working Group has resurrected Behavioral Extensions to CSS.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_14_2007_36421" class="2007-02-14T10:07:01Z">
<p>
The W3C CSS Working Group has resurrected <a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/WD-becss-20070205/">Behavioral Extensions to CSS</a>.
"Behavioral Extensions provide a way to link to binding technologies, such as XBL, from CSS style sheets. This allows bindings to be selected using the CSS cascade, and thus enables bindings to transparently benefit from the user style sheet mechansim, media selection, and alternate style sheets." In brief this proposes a new <code>binding</code> property that can locate rendering descriptions in another document:
</p>

<pre xml:space="preserve"><code>input[type="checkbox"] {
  binding: url("http://example.org/htmlBindings.xml#checkbox");
}
</code></pre>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_14_2007_36421"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_14_2007_36421</id>
    <updated>2007-02-14T10:07:01Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C Web Application Formats Working Group has posted a working draft of Widgets 1.0 Requirements.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_14_2007_36251" class="2007-02-14T10:04:11Z">

<img src="images/newicon.png" alt="" width="90" height="54" hspace="5" vspace="5" border="0" align="left"/>
<p>
The W3C Web Application Formats
Working Group has posted a working draft of <a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/WD-widgets-reqs-20070209/">Widgets 1.0 Requirements</a>. The goal is to 
</p>

<blockquote>
<p> standardize the way client-side web applications (widgets) are to be scripted, digitally signed, secured, packaged and deployed in a way that is device independent.
</p>

<p>
The type of web applications that are addressed by this document are usually small client-side applications for displaying and updating remote data, packaged in a way to allow a single download and installation on a client machine. The application may execute outside of the typical web browser interface. Examples include clocks, stock tickers, currency converters, news readers, games and weather forecasters. Some existing industry solutions go by the names "widgets", "gadgets" or "modules".
</p>

</blockquote>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_14_2007_36251"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_14_2007_36251</id>
    <updated>2007-02-14T10:04:11Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C Voice Browser Activity has published the proposed recommedation of Semantic Interpretation for Speech Recognition (SISR) Version 1.0.</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_14_2007_36132" class="2007-02-14T10:02:12Z">
<p>
The W3C Voice Browser Activity has published the proposed recommedation of
<a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/PR-semantic-interpretation-20070205/">Semantic Interpretation for Speech Recognition (SISR) Version 1.0</a>.
</p>

<blockquote>
<p>
This document defines the process of Semantic Interpretation for Speech Recognition and the syntax and semantics of semantic interpretation tags that can be added to speech recognition grammars to compute information to return to an application on the basis of rules and tokens that were matched by the speech recognizer. In particular, it defines the syntax and semantics of the contents of Tags in the Speech Recognition Grammar Specification [SRGS].
</p>

<p>
The results of semantic interpretation describe the meaning of a natural language utterance. The current specification represents this information as an ECMAScript object, and defines a mechanism to serialize the result into XML. The W3C Multimodal Interaction Activity [MMI] is defining an XML data format [EMMA] for containing and annotating the information in user utterances. It is expected that the EMMA language will be able to integrate results generated by Semantic Interpretation for Speech Recognition.
</p>

</blockquote>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_14_2007_36132"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_14_2007_36132</id>
    <updated>2007-02-14T10:02:12Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>IBM's developerWorks has published Ten predictions for XML in 2007.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_13_2007_43265" class="2007-02-13T12:01:05Z">
<p>
IBM's developerWorks has published 
<a shape="rect" href="http://www-128.ibm.com/developerworks/xml/library/x-xml2007predictions.html">	
Ten predictions for XML in 2007</a>. In this article, I peer into my crystal ball, and predict what we're likely to see happen to XML over the coming year. In brief:
 </p>

<blockquote>
2007 is shaping up to be the most exciting year since the community drove off the XML highway into the Web services swamp half a decade ago. XQuery, Atom, Atom Publishing Protocol (APP), XProc, and GRRDL are all promising new power. Some slightly older technologies like XForms and XSLT are having new life breathed into them. 2007 will be a very good year to work with XML.
</blockquote>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_13_2007_43265"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_13_2007_43265</id>
    <updated>2007-02-13T12:01:05Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Michael Kay has released version 8.9 of Saxon, his XSLT 2.0 and XQuery processor for Java and .NET.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_12_2007_49307" class="2007-02-12T14:42:47Z">
<p>
 Michael Kay has released <a shape="rect" href="http://www.saxonica.com/documentation/changes/intro.html">version 8.9</a> of Saxon, his XSLT 2.0 and XQuery processor for Java and .NET. Saxon can now compile a query to Java source code. It includes a Saxon specific Ant task. 
This release also adds support for XInclude.
</p>


<p>
Saxon is published in two versions for both of which 
Java 1.4 or later (or .NET) is required.
<a shape="rect" href="http://saxon.sf.net/">Saxon 8.9B</a> is an open source product  
published under the Mozilla Public License 1.0 that 
"implements the 'basic' conformance level for XSLT 2.0 and XQuery."
Saxon <a shape="rect" href="http://www.saxonica.com/">8.9SA</a> is a 
&#xA3;250.00 payware version that "allows stylesheets and queries to import an XML Schema, to validate input and output trees against a schema, and to select elements and attributes based on their schema-defined type. Saxon-SA also incorporates a free-standard XML Schema validator.
In addition Saxon-SA incorporates some advanced extensions not available in the Saxon-B product. These include a try/catch capability for catching dynamic errors, improved error diagnostics, support for higher-order functions, and additional facilities in XQuery including support for grouping, advanced regular expression analysis, and formatting of dates and numbers." 
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_12_2007_49307"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_12_2007_49307</id>
    <updated>2007-02-12T14:42:47Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recordare has released Dolet 3.6 for Finale, a $129.95 payware plug-in for reading and writing MusicXML files.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_11_2007_25726" class="2007-02-11T07:09:46Z">
<p>
Recordare has released <a shape="rect" href="http://store.recordare.com/dolet3fin.html">Dolet 3.6 for Finale</a>, a $129.95 payware 
plug-in for reading and writing MusicXML files.
This release fixes assorted bugs.
Finale is required.
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_11_2007_25726"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_11_2007_25726</id>
    <updated>2007-02-11T07:09:46Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Mozilla Project has posted the second alpha of Firefox 3.0 for Mac, Linux, and Windows.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_9_2007_26244" class="2007-02-09T07:17:24Z">
<p>
The Mozilla Project has posted the <a shape="rect" href="http://www.mozilla.org/projects/firefox/3.0a2/releasenotes/">second alpha of  Firefox 3.0</a> for Mac, Linux, and Windows. 
This release should be ACID2 compliant for the first time, though I haven't yet tested it. It also implements  the Web Apps 1.0 API for changing stylesheets
and supports CSS 2.1's <code>inline-block</code>s and <code>inline-table</code>s.
Furthermore, "XML documents can now be rendered as they're downloaded instead of only after the full document has been loaded."
JavaScript and DOM are also more standard.
Windows 2000 or later and Mac OS X 10.3.9 or later or Linux are required.
Windows 98 and earlier and Mac OS X 10.2 and earlier are no longer supported. 
Final release is not expected for another year. 
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_9_2007_26244"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_9_2007_26244</id>
    <updated>2007-02-09T07:17:24Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joerg Moebius has posted a new alpha release of yax, an open source (LGPL) implementation of XProc.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_8_2007_36038" class="2007-02-08T10:01:38Z">
<p>
Joerg Moebius has posted a new alpha release of  <a shape="rect" href="http://yax.sourceforge.net/">yax</a>, an open source (LGPL) implementation of 
<a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2006/WD-xproc-20061117/">XProc</a>. Components include:
</p>
<ul>

 
	<li>  Pipeline</li>
	<li>Choose/When/Otherwise</li>
	<li>Try/Group/Catch</li>
	<li> XSLT</li>
	<li>  XInclude</li>
	<li>   Load</li>
	<li>Store</li>
	<li>Identity</li>
	<li> Parameter</li>
	<li> Pipeline-Library</li>
</ul>




</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_8_2007_36038"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_8_2007_36038</id>
    <updated>2007-02-08T10:01:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Notation Software has released Notation Composer, a $150 notation editor and MIDI sequencer for Windows that can convert MIDI files into music notation and MusicXML.</title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_7_2007_33633" class="2007-02-07T09:21:33Z">

<img src="images/newicon.png" alt="" width="90" height="54" hspace="5" vspace="5" border="0" align="left"/>
<p>
Notation Software has released 
<a shape="rect" href="http://store.recordare.com/notationcomp.html">Notation Composer</a>, a $150 
notation editor and MIDI sequencer for Windows that can convert 
 MIDI files into music notation and MusicXML.<br clear="all"/>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_7_2007_33633"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_7_2007_33633</id>
    <updated>2007-02-07T09:21:33Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Myriad Software has released PDFtoMusic Pro, a $199 payware product that "turns PDF files created by notation programs (e.g.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_7_2007_33482" class="2007-02-07T09:18:02Z">

<img src="images/newicon.png" alt="" width="90" height="54" hspace="5" vspace="5" border="0" align="left"/>
<p>
Myriad Software has released 
<a shape="rect" href="http://store.recordare.com/pdftomusicpro.html">PDFtoMusic Pro</a>, a $199 payware product that  "turns PDF
files created by notation programs (e.g. they have vector graphics,
font data, etc., not just pixels from an image) into MusicXML files.
This is huge for unlocking the sheet music created in older programs,
or those that still don't support MusicXML, and getting them into more
modern, open programs."<br clear="all"/>
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_7_2007_33482"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_7_2007_33482</id>
    <updated>2007-02-07T09:18:02Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Big Faceless Organization has released the Big Faceless Report Generator 1.1.34, a $1200 payware Java application for converting XML documents to PDF.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_7_2007_33255" class="2007-02-07T09:14:15Z">
<p>
 	The  Big Faceless Organization has released the <a shape="rect" href="http://big.faceless.org/products/report?referrer=aff00017747">Big Faceless
	 Report Generator 1.1.34</a>, a $1200 payware Java application
	 for converting XML documents to PDF. Unlike most similar tools
	 it appears to be based on HTML and CSS rather than XSL
	 Formatting Objects. This is mostly a bug fix release.
	 Java 1.2 or later is required.
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_7_2007_33255"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_7_2007_33255</id>
    <updated>2007-02-07T09:14:15Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kiyut has released Sketsa 4.1, a $49 payware SVG editor written in Java.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_7_2007_32973" class="2007-02-07T09:10:33Z">
<p>
Kiyut has released
<a shape="rect" href="http://www.kiyut.com/products/sketsa/">Sketsa 4.1</a>, a $49 payware SVG editor written in Java.
Version 4.1 adds Union, Subtract, Intersect, ExclusiveOr, Path Combine, and
Path Break. 
Java 5 or later is required. 
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_7_2007_32973"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_7_2007_32973</id>
    <updated>2007-02-07T09:10:33Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>John Cowan has released TagSoup 1.0.3, an open source, Java-language, SAX parser for nasty, ugly HTML.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_6_2007_49197" class="2007-02-06T14:40:57Z">
<p>
John Cowan has released  <a shape="rect" href="http://www.ccil.org/~cowan/XML/tagsoup">TagSoup 1.0.3</a>,
an open source, Java-language, SAX parser for nasty, ugly HTML. 
This release should now run on pre-1.6 VMs. 
</p>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_6_2007_49197"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_6_2007_49197</id>
    <updated>2007-02-06T14:40:57Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The W3C WebCGM Working Group has released WebCGM 2.0, an updated version of the ISO Computer Graphics Metafile standard (ISO/IEC 8632:1999).
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_5_2007_50714" class="2007-02-05T14:05:14Z">
<p>
The W3C WebCGM Working Group has released
<a shape="rect" href="http://www.w3.org/TR/2007/REC-webcgm20-20070130/">WebCGM 2.0</a>, an updated version of the ISO Computer Graphics Metafile standard (ISO/IEC 8632:1999).
"WebCGM 2.0 adds a DOM (API) specification for programmatic access to WebCGM objects, and a specification of an XML Companion File (XCF) architecture, for externalization of non-graphical metadata. WebCGM 2.0, in addition, builds upon and extends the graphical and intelligent content of WebCGM 1.0, delivering functionality that was forecast for WebCGM 1.0, but was postponed in order to get the standard and its implementations to users expeditiously."
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_5_2007_50714"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_5_2007_50714</id>
    <updated>2007-02-05T14:05:14Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>John Cowan has released TagSoup 1.0.2, an open source, Java-language, SAX parser for nasty, ugly HTML.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_4_2007_27213" class="2007-02-04T08:34:33Z">
<p>
John Cowan has released  <a shape="rect" href="http://www.ccil.org/~cowan/XML/tagsoup">TagSoup 1.0.2</a>,
an open source, Java-language, SAX parser for nasty, ugly HTML. 
This release:
</p>


<ul>
	<li>Removes the Version attribute from the <code>html</code> element</li>
	<li>trims leading and trailing hyphens from comments</li>
	<li>Adds  --output-encoding switch to control the encoding</li>
	<li>Does not generate character references when the output encoding is Unicode.</li>
	<li>Compresses whitespace and strips junk from public identifiers</li>
</ul>



</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_4_2007_27213"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_4_2007_27213</id>
    <updated>2007-02-04T08:34:33Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Stefan Champailler has released DTDDoc 1.1.0, a JavaDoc like tool for creating HTML documentation of document type definitions from embedded DTD comments.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_4_2007_33649" class="2007-02-04T09:21:49Z">
<p> Stefan Champailler has released <a shape="rect" href="http://dtddoc.sourceforge.net/">DTDDoc 1.1.0</a>,   a
JavaDoc like tool for creating HTML documentation of document
type definitions from embedded DTD comments. It includes an Ant task and a Maven 2 plug-in. This release adds DTD source highlighting.
DTDDoc
is published under an MIT license. </p>

</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_4_2007_33649"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_4_2007_33649</id>
    <updated>2007-02-04T09:21:49Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ActiveState has released Komodo 4.0.1, a $295 payware IDE for Perl, Ruby, PHP, Python, Tcl, AJAX, and XSLT.
          </title>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" id="February_4_2007_33751" class="2007-02-04T09:23:31Z">
<p>
ActiveState has released  <a shape="rect" href="http://www.activestate.com/Products/Komodo/">Komodo 4.0.1</a>, a $295 payware 
<acronym title="integrated development environment">IDE</acronym> for Perl, Ruby, PHP, Python, Tcl, AJAX, and <em>XSLT</em>. Komodo runs on Mac OS X 10.3 and later, Linux, and Windows.  
</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <link href="/#February_4_2007_33751"/>
    <id>http://www.cafeconleche.org/#February_4_2007_33751</id>
    <updated>2007-02-04T09:23:31Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Web Browser CSS Support</title>
    <link href="http://www.webdevout.net/browser-support-css"/>
    <author>
      <name>www.webdevout.net</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.webdevout.net/browser-support-css</id>
    <updated>2007-02-19T08:18:10Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debtors Search for Discipline via Blogs </title>
    <link href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/02/18/us/18debt.html?ex=1329454800&amp;en=39a324f3f935ebac&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss"/>
    <author>
      <name>New York Times</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.nytimes.com/2007/02/18/us/18debt.html?ex=1329454800&amp;en=39a324f3f935ebac&amp;ei=5090&amp;partner=rssuserland&amp;emc=rss</id>
    <updated>2007-02-18T10:47:01Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>XML.com: Introducing RDFa</title>
    <link href="http://www.xml.com/pub/a/2007/02/14/introducing-rdfa.html"/>
    <author>
      <name>www.xml.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.xml.com/pub/a/2007/02/14/introducing-rdfa.html</id>
    <updated>2007-02-18T08:17:04Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Comcast Customer Uses "Unlimited Service" Excessively, Gets Disconnected For A Year </title>
    <link href="http://www.consumerist.com/search/comcast%20comcast-customer-uses-unlimited-service-excessively-gets-disconnected-for-a-year-235585.php"/>
    <author>
      <name>www.consumerist.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.consumerist.com/search/comcast%20comcast-customer-uses-unlimited-service-excessively-gets-disconnected-for-a-year-235585.php</id>
    <updated>2007-02-18T08:52:03Z</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
